Software Engineer

Erik Skoog

www.skoog.codes

Summary

A Software Engineer with 4 years of experience in object-oriented programming, development, testing, debugging, and product/development management. Motivated to grow and diversify through experience as a Software Engineer. Experience managing a 5-member team and coordinating with business stakeholders to successfully deliver software driven towards discovering business insights.

Experience

August 2021 - Current

Development Manager UNL Raikes Design Studio

Technologies: .NET, Neo4j, Azure Devops

- Develop a scalable, automated process for uploading data to a remote Neo4j server
- Implement dynamic, asynchronous functions for creating relationships and insights within
- Implement a pipeline with automated testing to be run on a nightly basis
- Manage squad commitments for each sprint through user stories and Git VCS

June 2021 - Current

Software Engineer Intern *Medical Solutions*

Technologies: React, TypeScript, Node

- Develop architecture and solution for a Timesheet service to reach 2,500+ monthly users
- Create testing strategies for new and existing services
- Create/maintain reusable software components within the Medical Solutions domain
- Engineer architecture for new services by identifying vulnerabilities in performance, readability, and maintainability

June 2020 - August 2020

Software Engineer Intern Spreetail

Technologies: .NET, React

- Designed and implemented APIs to use within Spreetail's internal software systems
- Built web-based software with .NET, SQL Server, and JavaScript to solve business problems faced by the Spreetail team and associated fulfillment centers
- Communicated directly with stakeholders and team members through project iterations

Featured Project

CrossGuard HackKU 2020

Technologies: Google Maps API, Flutter, Dart

- Created a cross-platform mobile application that aids blind individuals with navigating busy streets on foot. The application utilizes the Google Cloud API to navigate and Accuweather's API to create predictions for walking conditions.
- 3rd-place winning project

Education

August 2018 - May 2022 Software Engineering

University of Nebraska-Lincoln

(Minors: Mathematics, Music Technology) GPA: 3.750

Skills

- Software Engineering
- Project Management
- Product Releases
- Code Reviews
- Writing/Communication
- Software Testing

Top Technologies

- React
- **TypeScript**
- .NET
- Python
- Git VCS

Contact

4416 Oakwood Lane West Des Moines, IA (515)-421-2171

euskoog@gmail.com Portfolio: www.skoog.codes